if you understand supply and demand
trading you can take some amazing trades
and build real consistency within your
work so this video is The Ultimate Guide
to supply and demand I'm going to show
you what it is why it happens and how
you can use it to develop a consistent
strategy that brings you profit within
the markets so let's get into it a quick
note before we go deeper into supply and
demand trading I have a free 70-minute
training that you can sign up to right
now within this we go over supply and
demand we go over liquidity order flow
risk control and a bunch of different
concepts which will improve your trading
scan this QR code or head over to the
link in the description and you can sign
up to that right now for free let's get
back into the video so first of all
let's start out by talking about the
basic premise of supply and demand now
in a nutshell supply and demand refers
to large buying moves or large selling
moves in the market and it is formulated
not by the amount of buyers and sellers
but instead by the amount of buying or
selling meaning it doesn't have to be
millions of sellers at one level or
millions of buyers at one level but it
can instead be a few participants
putting huge order Zone at set levels so
the basic theory is that supply and
demand is driven by institutional orders
and where possible we want to follow
those orders to take our own trades
because this is where the big profits
and the consistent moves are going to
come from so Supply is a large selling
move it is basically where a lot of
suppliers been brought to the market and
we see prices decline Demand on the
other hand is a large buying move where
we see a lot of demand come into the
market a lot of buying takes place and
this drives the price up very quickly
and to give you a very simplified and
easy way to understand why supply and
demand is useful we can look at it from
a pure pricing standpoint so using this
as an example then we're going to look
at this area of demand within this
market so from a pure pricing standpoint
we can see that this area between
1.11528
and
1.10618 is a price that people were
happy to pay for the pound versus the US
dollar now if we see this as a price
where people were happy to pay for this
in the past we can assume that this is
going to be a price that people are
happy to pay in the future so the idea
is then if price can pull all the way
back down to this range we can also buy
at this preset well-priced level so
basically we're looking to get ourselves
a bargain now the range that we get at
the bottom of a large demand move or at
the top of a large Supply move can be
identified as a zone so this area here
would be a demand Zone and if we were
looking at this from the other
perspective on the sell side this would
be a supply Zone from here what we want
to see is price return towards this
demand Zone and when it does we have a
good price to buy from
[Music]
so now that we covered the basics of
supply and demand let me show you how to
Mark out zones now there is a general
rule in the trading community that to
Mark out a supply or demand Zone you
should use the last down candle before
an up move or the last up candle before
a down move so this being a sideways
candle would be an accurate demand Zone
and for a move like this you would focus
on the last down candle okay so that
would be your demand zone now I don't
use this general rule as I self-taught
myself supply and demand using very
basic tidbits of information I actually
developed myself a different rule okay I
learned to plan demand in a different
way but I found this way to be very
beneficial because I think it gives me
the best results so it's totally up to
you whether you follow the general rule
or you go with the approach that I go
with but my Approach is to use the last
candle before the impulse so if we look
here we have this demand area and this
big demand push-up so what I'm going to
do is identify the last candle before
the impulse which is this one and use
that as as my Demento so as you can see
with this buying idea price filled into
this and we could have got a nice entry
and a safe stop loss and survived the
move whereas if you were using the
traditional supply and demand rules and
you were entering like this the wick
would have actually gone below your Zone
and potentially taking you out of the
trade now I'm not saying that my way is
right and everyone else is wrong it will
be personal to you and I'm sure if you
trade with the standard rule you'll do
just fine but for an insight into how I
view it that is what I do the last
candle before the impulse so looking at
this current structure let me give you
an example of how I would plot my demand
zones so this is a demand Zone here
because we have the last candle before
this large impulse we fall back in we
get a buy this then becomes a demand
Zone being the last candle before this
large impulse we come back in and we get
to buy and as you can see here we had
this large impulse and here's a tip for
you if you've got very tricky price
action to work with like this what you
can do is actually use the Wicks of
these moves now the reason a wick is
okay in a scenario like this is because
simply the wick covers this entire range
by using the wick this is going to be
quite a high probability area to buy
from in the future now as you can see
not every demand zone is going to get
hit there's also a demand Zone here
which hasn't been retested yet now it
may do some point in the future but not
every single one is going to provide a
trade for example if you looked at this
very clear demand Zone you would have
actually missed out on this initial
movement because price didn't come to
retest it but that's just the nature of
probabilities that we have in trading
and this is something that can't really
be entirely avoided and in terms of
plotting on Supply zones it works in the
very same way so for this example all
I've done is flip the chart upside down
so you can see on a sell side how we
would plot the supply zones okay so one
important thing that you will notice by
looking at this is that we are always
moving with the trend and this is a very
important thing to understand you can
only trade supply and demand with Market
structure if you try to trade supply and
demand without an understanding of the
overall trend Direction in the market
then you are not going to do very well
you because simply put supply and demand
zones will appear everywhere but it's up
to you to work out which ones are
actually valid by following the trend
structure so if we're looking at this
from a selling perspective then we can
see that this is actually a downtrend
from this point we broke the structure
here and we've had a lower low lower
high lower low lower high lower low so
all we would want to do within this
trend is sell from Supply zones we don't
want to focus on any demand zones
whatsoever because if we do as you can
see we will continually be taken out and
the reason for that is because we are
battling the trend and if the trend is
down the only thing we should be doing
is trying to follow that not fight
against it and flipping it around the
same goes for buying in an uptrend if
the market is trending upwards we only
want to buy demand zones we do not want
to attempt to sell any of the supply
zones that form because we will be
continually taken out and stack up a
bunch of losses that we don't want to
encounter so to recap on the talking
points so far supply and demand is
driven by large amounts of buying or
selling in a market supply is on the
sell side and indicates a big amount of
selling pressure and demand is on the
buy side and indicates a large amount of
buying pressure supply and demand
indicate prices that were previously
seen as good levels to buy or sell from
therefore we can assume when price
returns to these levels it will once
again be a good price to actually buy
into the market or sell into the market
from the next point is that supply and
demand should always be used with the
trend meaning we should only be buying
demand zones if the market is trending
to the upside we should only be selling
Supply zones if the market is trending
to the downside we never want to battle
the market because if we do we will
Stack Up losses very very quickly so now
what we're going to do is look at a
couple of example trades using supply
and demand and showing you how to put
supply and demand together with Market
structure to catch consistent winning
trades for our first trade example let's
take a look at gold here we can see a
market that has been up trending solidly
we had this very large pullback down but
since hitting this demand Zone here
we've actually had a break of structure
to the upside which you can see just
here
so now we have this High time frame
confirmation so now we have this High
time frame Trend pairing with this break
of structure after retesting a demand
Zone indicating that maybe we could be
due to move to the upside now supply and
demand can be used for targets now
supply and demand can be used for
entries and it can also be used for
targets pretty much every trade I get
into is either going to be targeting a
point of liquidity which is a topic for
another video or an imbalanced supply
and demand zone so if we were looking to
buy this we would buy from the demand
Zone which is just down here and if we
were looking for a Target we would use a
clear imbalanced Supply or demand Zone
much like this one just here
and maybe even these ones up in the high
of the move so for this example let's
actually set three different take profit
levels that we can Target following this
break of structure and buying from the
demand Zone the trade that we set up
will look something like this we want to
buy the demand Zone we can put our stop
loss beneath the low of the move and
then we can Target through into each of
these levels and as price moves we can
take profit along the way and let's see
how it goes
foreign
[Music]
and there we have it a trade following
the high time frame Trend buying from
demand and targeting imbalanced Supply
zones for the profit taking on this
position as you can see it's a very
simple system but when you pair Market
structure with supplier demand you can
take some really really great trades now
full disclosure unfortunately I didn't
hold my trade this long I got myself and
my team into this position down here in
this low time frame price action however
we were looking at this from a different
perspective and due to some fundamentals
I decided to take the profits early so
we targeted this imbalance Supply here
and used a very low time frame 15 minute
and 30 minute demand to buy from this
point up to this point now in the end it
still turned out to be an 8 Hour trade
which was very big anyway but a very
useful piece of information to take from
that lesson is that even though I didn't
take this full trade up I still locked
in a solid profit using Demand on the
low time frame from here up to here and
what does that show well that shows that
supply and demand is relevant on all
time frames you can apply this system to
the one minute and the five min if you
are a low time frame day trader if
you're a swing Trader you can use supply
and demand in this method to trade the
four hour and daily time frames it
really doesn't matter what time frames
you're using supply and demand is a
fractal concept meaning it will move the
same across pretty much every time frame
and allow you to adapt your system to
your personal trading style so for our
final trade example let's take a look at
that exact trade that I sent out to my
students this is the same price action
but seen on a lower time frame and this
is what we were focused on what you can
see here is a demand Zone reaction just
there from this previous move of demand
now we can see there is a big selling
move showing there is a supply Zone and
that is going to be our imbalance Supply
Zone Target which I will use as this
candle here being the last candle before
the down move being the last candle
before the big downside impulse
so if we look at the structure down here
then what we can see is that we had a
lower low a lower high a lower low and
then we broke up to a higher height so
the break of structure I was interested
in for this position was this one just
here
now we saw then the market come down and
form a higher low and what we actually
did then was break some lower time frame
structure so I used the concepts of
supply and demand to get us into a
position from here and the trade given
from that lower time frame usage of
supply and demand would look something
like this we're looking to enter from
the demand Zone with a stop loss beneath
the low and we're going to Target that
in Balance supply for our profit taking
and now let's see how that played out
foreign
[Music]
so as you can see supply and demand is
not rigid to one time frame you can
apply this on the lower time frames or
the higher time frames and it will bring
you some really really nice results and
that brings us to the end of the video I
hope you've enjoyed this guide on supply
and demand trading and now what I want
you to do is go ahead to the markets and
back test this for yourself to develop
your consistency with a supply and
demand trading system now it does take
some time to master supply and demand
and to understand which zones you should
be focusing on but all you need to
remember is that you have to move with
the trend if you do this you can get
some really solid results week by week
and month by month and build yourself a
profitable trading system using the very
simple concepts of structure and supply
and demand in conjunction I hope you've
enjoyed this video if you have make sure
you subscribe to my channel because I
post educational videos here every
single week thank you for watching and
I'll see you in the next one
foreign